Guide to the Richard Moser Collection on the GI Anti-Vietnam War Movement and Lordstown (Ohio) Automobile Workers TAM.544
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Richard Moser Collection on the GI Anti-Vietnam War Movement and Lordstown (Ohio) Automobile Workers
1970s-1990s
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Moser, Richard R., 1952-
TAM.544
4.5 Linear Feet (6 boxes)
Richard Moser was an associate professor of American history at Middle Tennessee State University until 1998, and the author of The New Winter Soldiers: GI and Veteran Dissent during the Vietnam Era (1996). The Richard Moser Collection on the GI Anti-Vietnam War Movement and Lordstown (Ohio) Automobile Workers consists of oral history recordings with summaries and transcripts, as well as academic materials from Moser's students.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Richard Moser in 2010. The accession number associated with this gift is 2010.054.
Appraisal
In September 2025, 3 audiocassettes with duplicative content were deaccessioned. In December 2025, 2 audiocassettes with duplicative content were deaccessioned.
Biographical Note
Richard Moser earned his PhD from Rutgers University in 1992. Until 1998, he was an associate professor of American history at Middle Tennessee State University. He is the author of The New Winter Soldiers: GI and Veteran Dissent during the Vietnam Era (1996) and, with Van Gosse, is co-editor of The World the Sixties Made: Politics and Culture in Recent America (2003). He has also served as the National Organizer of the American Association of University Professors.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to some audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Audiovisual materials that have not been preserved may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact NYU Special Collections (special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596) with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Scope and Contents
The Richard Moser Collection on the GI Anti-Vietnam War Movement and Lordstown (Ohio) Automobile Workers consists of oral history audio recordings, along with their summaries and transcripts. The recordings pertain to the GI anti-Vietnam War movement, as well as rank and file labor movement activity during the 1970s at the Lordstown, Ohio General Motors plant, whose workers were represented by the United Automobile Workers Local 112. Some interviews were conducted contemporaneously, others subsequently. The collection also includes research notes, some correspondence, printed ephemera, and papers written by Moser's students.
Separated Materials
One box of GI anti-Vietnam War serials were separated to the Library's print collection, as was one box of books and pamphlets.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist.
Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Protest movements -- United States.; Soldiers -- United States -- Political activity; Lordstown (Ohio); Automobile industry workers -- Ohio -- Lordstown.; Oral histories (literary works); Audiocassettes.; Videocassettes.; Interviews.; International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Local 1112 (Lordstown, Ohio); Moser, Richard R., 1952-
- Lordstown Oral Histories, June 1996 - June 1997; cuid15025 (Box 1)
  - Joe Santiago, June 17, 1997; cuid17590 (Box 1, Audiocassette 544_1, 544_2, 544_3, 544_4)
  - Jim Tripp, June 10, 1996; cuid17589
    - Jim Tripp Tape 2, July 10, 1996; cuid17589A (Box 1, Audiocassette TAM_544_7)
    - Paul Cubellis / Jim Tripp Tape 2, undated; cuid17589B (Box 1, Audiocassette TAM_544_22)
    - Jim Tripp Tape 2, Side 1 Copy / Buzz Doyle 2, undated; cuid44893 (Box 1, Audiocassette TAM_544_10)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Duration: 51 minutes.
  - Bob Guthridge, July 11, 1996; cuid17591 (Box 1, Audiocassette 544_12, 544_13)
  - Irving Bluestone, Detroit, July 8, 1996; cuid17592 (Box 1, Audiocassette 544_14, 544_15, 544_16, 544_17, 544_18, 544_19)
  - Paul Cubellis, July 10, 1996; cuid17593 (Box 1, Audiocassette 544_20, 544_21, 544_22, 544_23, 544_24)
  - Bob Price, August 11, 1996 (Box 1, Audiocassette 544_25, 544_26, 544_27, 544_28, 544_29)
  - David "Buzz" Doyle, May 18, 1997 (Box 1, Audiocassette 544_30, 544_31, 544_32)
  - Ray Lewis, June 18, 1997 (Box 1, Audiocassette 544_33, 544_34, Box Shared Tamiment 086, Audiocassette 544_35, 544_36)
  - Mike Aurilio, June 20, 1997 (Box Shared Tamiment 086, Audiocassette 544_37, 544_38, 544_39, 544_40)
- Vietnam GI movement Oral Histories, March 1988 - October 1990; cuid44043 (Box 2)
  - Dave Cline, February 15 - March 1, 1988
    - Tape 1, March 1, 1988; cuid15026 (Box 2, Box Shared Tamiment 111)
    - Tape 3, February 15, 1988; cuid15028 (Box 2, Box Shared Tamiment 111)
      Preservation note: Side 2: 00:00-00:25 technical problems with recorder commented on by interviewer. Problem is corrected and interview continues but at reduced volume.
    - Tape 4, March 1, 1988; cuid15027 (Box 2, Box Shared Tamiment 111)
  - Susan Schnall, October 25, 1990
    - Part 1, cuid15029 (Box 2, Box Shared Tamiment 111)
    - Part 2, cuid15030 (Box 2, Box Shared Tamiment 111)
  - Jan Berry, undated; cuid15038; 2 audiocassette Parts 1-4 of interview (Box 2, Cassette cuid15038A, cuid15038B)
    Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 63 min. [A] and 46 min. [B]
- Vietnam GI movement Oral Histories, December 1993; cuid44044 (Box 3)
  - Jim Pechin, Notre Dame, December 4, 1993; cuid15039; 1 audiocassette (Box 3, Cassette cuid15039)
    Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 50 min.
- Vietnam War Videocassettes: Documentaries, undated; cuid15031 (Box 4)
- The Invisible Force, undated; cuid15032 (Box 4)
- Only the Beginning, undated; cuid15033 (Box 4)
- Veterans film transfer, June 27, 1991; cuid15034 (Box 4)
- Disobeying Orders: GI Resistance to the Vietnam War, Produced by Pam Sporn, 1990; cuid15035 (Box 4)
- Vietnam GI Movement Research Files (including interview summaries and transcripts), cuid15036 (Box 5)
- Lordstown Research Files (including interview summaries and transcripts), cuid15037 (Box 6)